International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Stulberg, Louis, President. Correspondence, 1945-1977 [bulk 1966-1975]. 5780/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- II. Non-union correspondence.
  - Complaints: 1974., Re Eufaula Fashions, Eufaula, Ala.; includes grievance reports. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Complaints: Sept-Dec. 1973. (Box 28, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Complaints: Jan-Aug. 1973. (Box 28, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Complaints: 1972. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Associations, Trade. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Attorneys. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - City, State and Federal Officials. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Employers in Garment Industry. (Box 29, Folder 5a-5b)
  - Foreign. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Impartial Chairmen. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Officers and Members. (Box 29, Folder 8a-8c)
  - Organizations. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Personal. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Political. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Press. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 30, Folder 4a-4c)
  - Congratulatory Messages upon being elected to the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO, 1968. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Consumer Affairs, President's Committee: 1967-69. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers, Inc.,: 1969, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Cost-of-Living Wage Adjustments: 1972., Includes correspondence on Cost-of-Living Council not to decontrol wages in the apparel industry. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - D: 1966-75. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Democratic Labor Advisory Council: 1974. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Democratic National Committee: 1969-75., Includes correspondence with Robert Strauss; requests for Union contributions and support for telethon. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Dino Boutiques, Inc.: 1968., Re strike. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - E: 1967-75. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Eighty-five Fifteen (85-15) Per Cent Problem, Health and Welfare Funds: 1969., Correspondence with Legal Dept. re tax on Health and Welfare Funds. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - F: 1966-77., Includes correspondence with Forward (Jewish Daily). (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Fashion Capital of the World, Inc., NYC: 1973-74. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology: 1973-75. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Foreign: 1969-77. (Box 31, Folder 6a)
  - Foreign, England: 1972-73., Incl, Stulberg address at British Trades Union Congress meeting, 1972. (Box 31, Folder 6b)
  - Foreign, Italy: 1973-75. (Box 31, Folder 6c)
  - Foreign, Japan: 1967-75., Includes correspondence with Zensen Domei (Japan Federation of Textile Unions) re trade in the textile and garment industries. (Box 31, Folder 6d)
  - G: 1966-75. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Greetings: 1966-75., Arranged alphabetically by organization or union. (Box 31, Folder 8a-8b)
  - H: 1967-75. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Histadrut (N.Y.): 1967-75., Includes correspondence re Histadrut Humanitarian Award honoring Hubert H. Humphrey, May 1967. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Housing, International Basic Economy Corporation: 1966-67., Includes correspondence with J.C.Tyler, Jr. (Vice President), Housing group re Union mortgage commitment for David Dubinsky Park, Carolina, Puerto Rico. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Housing: 1967-75., Includes correspondence and reports from United Housing Foundation, Mutual Redevelopment Houses, Inc., Co-op City (Riverberg Corp.). (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - I: 1966-74. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Impartial Chairmen: 1973-74. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Imports: 1969-72., Includes Stulberg testimony before House of Representatives, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Israel: 1959-77., Includes corres, on purchasing Israeli Bonds. (Box 32, Folder 6a-6b)
  - Inter-American Textile and Garment Workers Federations 1966-75, Includes correspondence with Carlos Bedoya T. (General Secretary). (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers Federation (Brussels): 1968-76. (Box 32, Folder 8a-8b)
  - Invitations: 1972-77., Includes Four Freedoms Award to Stulberg and his speech at luncheon, 1972. (Box 33, Folder 1a)
  - J: 1967-75. (Box 33, Folder 1b)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: 1967-74. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Jonathan Logan, Inc.: 1967-77., Includes correspondence re negotiations. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Judy Bond: 1968. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Jurisdictional Disputes: 1973., Puritan Fashions, Wintex Plan (Newport, Tenn.). (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - K: 1967-75. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Kellwood Co.: 1966-67, 1972., Correspondence pertaining to strike at Ottenheimer Bros. manufacturing plant of Little Rock, a subsidiary of the Kellwood Corp. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Kemp, Maida Springer: 1966-72., Includes reports from Maida Kemp (Midwest Director), A. Philip Randolph Institute. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - L: 1967-75., Includes Stulberg statement to House Ways and Means Committee on Social Security (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - League for Industrial Democracy: 1973, 1975, Includes minutes of Board meeting. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Leslie Fay: 1967. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Liberal Party: 1966-74., Includes correspondence and memoranda on activities in New York; also controversy within Party, 1966-67. (Box 34, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Little Lisa Sales Co. and Precious Girl, Ltd.: 1968., Correspondence pertaining to jurisdictional dispute with Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. (Box 34, Folder 1a)
  - Lovestone, Jay: 1965-75., Correspondence, reports on international political and trade union activities and those of the AFL-CIO. (Box 34, Folder 2b)
  - M: 1966-77., Includes David H. Morse speech at convention of the United Steelworkers of America, Sept. 1974. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Maidenform, Inc.: 1965-73. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Marlene Industries Corp.: 1968-70. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Mayor's Committee on Exploitation of Workers: 1967, 1970-72., (Stulberg member) Includes memoranda to Committee members, minutes of meeting. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Minimum Wage: 1969. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Corres: 1967-75., Includes messages of congratulations and condolences. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - N: 1966-75. (Box 34, Folder 9a-9b)
  - National Association of Women's and Children's Apparel Salesmen: 1964-65., Includes newspaper clipping files on their unionizing activities. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - National Labor Relations Board: 1967-68, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Nelly Don, Inc.: 1968, 1970. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - New York City: 1966-74., Includes correspondence with John V. Lindsay and City officials re civic affairs, programs and legislation. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - New York City: Central Labor Committee, 1966-74. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - N.Y.C.: New York Urban Coalition, Inc., 1967-68., Stulberg, member. Board of Directors (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - New York Times; 1966-68., Includes Dubinsky's reply to article on Union exploitation of workers, Dec. 1966. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - O: 1966-75. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - P: 1968-76. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Politics: 1974-75., Includes ltrs. from candidates requesting contributions, candidates' programs; congratulatory messages and correspondence re 28 delegates-at-large selected by N.Y. Democratic Party Select Committee to mini-convention in Kansas City, 1974. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Politics: 1973. (Box 35, Folder 9a-9b)
  - Politics: 1972., Includes correspondence, leaflets, candidates' records on presidential election with ILGWU support of McGovern-Shriver ticket. (Box 35, Folder 10a-10b)
  - Politics: 1971. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Politics: 1970. (Box 36, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Politics: 1970. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Politics: 1970., Goldberg-Patterson campaign. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Politics: 1969., Includes statements by Stulberg on Social Security and public welfare, Nov. 14, 1969; on Unemployment Insurance submitted to the Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Rep., Oct. 3, 1969; on the nomination of Judge Clement Haynsworth, Jr., to the U.S. Supreme Court; campaign committee contributions; correspondence with candidates; Liberal Party politics; letter from Richard M. Nixon re inflation. (Box 36, Folder 5a-5b)
  - Politics: 1966-68., Includes correspondence on controversy bet. Liberal Party and Union in Liberal Party support of Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr. for governor of New York State, 1966. (Box 36, Folder 6a-6b)
  - Q: 1974. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - R: 1966-77., Includes correspondence with A. Philip Randolph and Bayard Rustin of the A. Philip Randolph Institute. (Box 37, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Retirees of ILGWU: Complaints, 1974., Includes complaints from Joseph Mangano of Local 48. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Retiree Complaints: 1973. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Retiree Complaints: 1971-72. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Retiree Complaints: 1969-70 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - S: 1966-76. (Box 37, Folder 7a-7b)
  - Special Assistance Fund: 1966-67., (David Dubinsky, Administrator) Reports from Zalmen Lichtenstein. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - T: 1966-75. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - U: 1966-74. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - AFL-CIO: 1974-77., Correspondence with George Meany, releases, statements on proposed legislation, committee meeting reports (Box 38, Folder 4a-4b)
  - AFL-CIO: 1973. (Box 38, Folder 5a-5b)
  - AFL-CIO: 1972. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - AFL-CIO: 1971. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - AFL-CIO: 1970. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO: 1969. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - AFL-CIO: 1968. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - AFL-CIO: 1966-67. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD), 1968-76., Records on expulsion of Otto Silva (regional director of AIFLD) from Trinidad and Tobago, 1972. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: African-American Labor Center (AALC), 1973-75, Includes report of activities for 1973, minutes of board of directors. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: Asian-American Free Labor Institute (AAFLI), 1972-74., Includes minutes of meetings, 1973-74. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1968-74, Letters, releases from Alexander Barkan (National Director). (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: Industrial Union Department (IUD), 1975., (Stulberg, Vice President) 1966-73) Includes reports from Democratic Study Group (House of Rep.). (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: IUD, 1974. (Box 40, Folder 3a-3b)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: IUD, 1970-73. (Box 40, Folder 4a-4b)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: IUD, 1966-69. (Box 40, Folder 5a-5b)
  - AFL-CIO Organizations: Labor Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance, 1969., Minutes of Twenty-ninth meeting, Sept. 1969. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1967-74., Includes correspondence re jurisdictional dispute. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of N.A., 1967-75. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: American Federation of Teachers, 1967-75., Includes complaints by Charles Cogen (President) against William Ross (member), Philadelphia Board of Education, 1967. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Textile Workers Union of America, 1972-74., Correspondence with William Pollock; jurisdictional disputes with Union. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: United Auto Workers, 1967-68, (independent) 1968-74., (International Union of Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Miscellaneous Union, 1967-76. (Box 41, Folder 7a-7c)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Office and Professional Employees International Union, 1967-76., Correspondence re contract negotiations for Union employees. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - AFL-CIO Affiliates: Union Labor Life Insurance Co., 1958-73., Includes correspondence re death benefit coverage of Union officers. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - United Nations: 1968-69., Includes congratulatory messages on Stulberg's appointment to represent U.S. in 25th General Assembly of UN, 1968? invitations; speech at 50th anniversary of ILO, 1969. (Box 42, Folder 1a-1b)
  - United Nations: "UN We Believe" Dinner, 1974. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - United States Government: 1967-75., (Arranged by correspondent) Includes congratulatory message from President Ford on Union's 75th Anniversary, 1975; ltrs. from Presidents Richard M. Nixon and Harry S Truman; correspondence with A.B.Trowbridge (Acting Secretary), Commerce, re International Clothing Fair (Odezhda) in Moscow, 1967; Willard Wirtz (Secretary), Labor, on labor legislation for women, 1967. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Government: House of Representatives, 1967-75., (Congressional correspondence, arranged by correspondent) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Government: U.S. Senate, 1972-74., (Arranged by correspondent) Includes correspondence with Jacob K. Javits, 1974-75; Edward M. Kennedy, 1972-74; Warren G. Magnuson on labor-related matters, 1974; George McGovern on 1972 presidential campaign. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Government: Humphrey, Hubert H., 1965-76. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Government: Johnson, Lyndon B., 1965-74. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - V: 1967-74. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - W: 1967-75. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Wage Freeze: 1971-72. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Workmen's Circle: 1967 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - X,Y,Z: 1966-74. (Box 42, Folder 12)
- III. Requests from organizations.
  Requests from organizations, foundations or individuals for ILGWU participation in fund-raising campaigns, dinners and donations. Arranged alphabetically by organization or individuals. Includes requests when Stulberg was Vice President and General Secretary-Treasurer, 1956-66.
  - Requests: A., Includes African-American Labor Institute, American Council for Nationalities Service. (Box 43, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Requests: AFL-CIO and Affiliates., Includes congratulatory messages to unions. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Requests: A., Includes American Jewish Committee (Box 43, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Requests: A., American Trade Union Council of the National Committee for Labor Israel (Histadrut). (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Requests: A., Includes Antonini Memorial in Catania, Sicily, Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation, Aspira of America, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 5a-5b)
  - Requests: B., Includes Boy Scouts of America. (Box 44, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Requests: B., Includes Brandeis University, Brooklyn Hebrew Home for the Aged, Bund Archives of the Labor Movement. (Box 44, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Requests: C., Includes Catholic Interracial Council of N.Y. (Box 44, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Requests: C., Includes Citizens Committee for Peace With Freedom in Vietnam, Citizens Housing and Planning Council of N.Y. (Box 44, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Requests: C., Committee on Political Education (COPE), Congress for Jewish Culture, Congress of Racial Equality (CORE). (Box 45, Folder 1a-1c)
  - Requests: D., Includes Democratic Socialist Federation of U.S. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Requests: E. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Requests: F., Includes Fair Campaign Practices Committee. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Requests: Fashion Institute of Technology (F.I.T.), 1960-72., Includes Correspondence and agreement on the Isidore Nagler Hall, 1960-61. (Box 45, Folder 5a-5c)
  - Requests: Foreign Policy Association (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Requests: Freedom House. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Requests: F., Includes Freie Arbeiter Stimme. (Box 46, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Requests: G., Golden Ring Clubs, Grand Street Boys Association. (Box 46, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Requests: H., (American) Heart Association, Histadrut. (Box 46, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Requests: I., Includes International Rescue Committee, (United) Italian-American Labor Council. (Box 46, Folder 5a-5b)
  - Requests: J. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Requests: Jewish Labor Committee Includes correspondence on 4th Annual Labor Rights Award Dinner in honor of Louis Stulberg, Nov. 1970. (Box 47, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Requests: J., Includes Jewish Socialist Verband. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Requests: K. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Requests: L., Includes Legal Aid Society, League for Industrial Democracy. (Box 47, Folder 5a-5b)
  - Requests: L., Includes League for Mutual Aid, Liberal Digest, Liberal Party. (Box 47, Folder 6a-6b)
  - Requests: M., Includes Muscular Dystrophy Association (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Requests: N., Includes National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), National Bureau of Economic Research, National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, National Committee for Rural Schools, National Conference of Christians and Jews. (Box 48, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Requests: N., Includes National Multiple Sclerosis, National Sharecroppers Fund, National Urban League. (Box 48, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Requests: N., Includes New Leader, New York Urban League. (Box 48, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Requests: O., Includes (American) Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training (ORT). (Box 49, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Requests: P., Includes Police Athletic League (P.A.O.), Protestant Council campaign. (Box 49, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Requests: R., Includes A. Philip Randolph Institute, Eleanor Roosevelt Golden Ring Club, FDR Four Freedoms Award, Roosevelt University. (Box 49, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Requests: S., Includes Salvation Army, Giuseppina Saragat Foundation, Scholarship, Education, and Defense Fund for Racial Equality (SEDFRE), Sholem Aleichem Folk Institute, Smith, Alfred E., Memorial Fund, Spanish Refugee Aid, and Southern Christian Leadership Conference. (Box 49, Folder 4a-4c)
  - Requests: T. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Requests: U., Includes United Jewish Appeal, United Nations (organizations), and Unser Stimme. (Box 50, Folder 2a-2c)
  - Requests: V. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Requests: W., Includes Weizman Institute of Science, Wiltwyck School and Workers Defense League. (Box 50, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Requests: Workmen's Circle. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Requests: Y., Includes Yeshiva University, YIVO (Yiddish Institute for Jewish Research), Young Peoples Socialist League. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Requests: Z., Includes The Zukunft. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums (& hospitals), A-B., (Arranged alphabetically by institution) Beth Abraham Hospital (Stulberg trustee), includes agreement made with Union and minutes of meeting. (Box 51, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums, City of Hope. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums, Deborah Hospital. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums, E-H. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums, I-M. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Requests: Sanatoriums, N-Z. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Copies of Box 42. (Box 51, Folder 7)
- IV. Personal correspondence.
  - Personal., Stulberg Awards, correspondence re establishment of the Louis Stulberg Chair of Brandeis University, 1969, Prime Minister's Medal on the occasion of the 25th Anniversary of the State of Israel, 1973. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Personal, 1976., Bank matters. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Personal, 1975., Get-well cards. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Personal, 1975., Get-well cards from retirees. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Personal, 1975., Letters re his retirement; includes letter retiring from office. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Personal., Photographs. (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Personal, 1973-77., Statements. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Personal, 1967., U.S. Information Agency. (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Personal, 1976-77. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Personal, 1975. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Personal, 1973-1974. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Personal, 1971-1972. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Personal, 1969-1970. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Personal, 1968. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Personal, 1967. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Personal, 1966., Includes congratulatory messages upon being elected President. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Personal, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Personal, 1964. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Personal, 1945-1963. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Books and Additional (Box 55)
  - Photographs (Box 56)